aao.org 2002-12-07

# AAO.org Privacy Policy

## Copyright

The American Academy of Ophthalmology owns the copyright in all contents of the aao.org website unless otherwise indicated. We present all such copyrighted material here for personal use only as long as the copyright notice and permission notice is included in your reproduction. We expressly prohibit reprints or electronic reproduction of any document in part or in its entirety, unless you obtain prior written consent from the American Academy of Ophthalmology or the owner of the material. Address all applications and inquiries to the contact cited on a particular page. 

## Disclaimer

The American Academy of Ophthalmology provides on-line information and services on the Internet as a benefit to its members and the public and to further its educational mission. 

1\. THE ACADEMY, ANY WEBSITE CONTRIBUTORS AND THEIR AFFILIATES DO NOT MAKE ANY WARRANTIES, AS TO THE ACCURACY, ADEQUACY OR COMPLETENESS OF ANY MATERIAL PRESENTED HERE, WHICH IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS. THE ACADEMY AND ITS WEBSITE CONTRIBUTORS ARE NOT LIABLE TO ANYONE FOR ANY: a) ERRORS, INACCURACIES, OMISSIONS OBTAINED HERE; b) DAMAGES OR INJURY TO PERSON OR PROPERTY FROM ANY USE OF IDEAS CONTAINED HERE; AND/OR c) ANY DAMAGES INCURRED IF MATERIAL INFECTS OR CONTAMINATES A USER'S SYSTEM. 

2\. The information published on the aao.org website is not intended to replace consultation with an ophthalmologist. The Academy cannot answer specific medical questions or refer you to a particular ophthalmologist. 

3\. Unless specifically stated otherwise, the opinions expressed and statements made by various authors on this website reflect the author's observations and do not imply endorsement by the Academy. 

4\. The Academy does not exert editorial control over and has not participated in the development of other Internet websites. The Academy does not support, endorse, or hold any responsibility for hyperlink pointers, their website content, any of their expressed views, any services they offer or hyperlinks they mention. The Academy does not endorse any of the products or companies mentioned in the aao.org website. 

## Trademarks

The following are all trademarks or registered trademarks of the American Academy of Ophthalmology: EyeNet, American Academy of Ophthalmology, AAO, The Foundation of the American Academy of Ophthalmology, Advocacy Update, Clinical Pearls, LEO (Lifelong Education for the Ophthalmologist), Eyecon: Diabetic Retinopathy Pilot, Ophthalmology, Vision for Your Future, Get an Eyeful, Celebrate Sight: Do You Know Your Glaucoma Risk?sm , National Eye Care Project (NECP), National Children's Eye Care Program (NCECP), Academy Services, Inc. (ASI), Academy Insurance Management Services, Inc. (AIMS), Diabetes 2000, Discover Your Eye Q, Test Your Eye-Q, ICODE, NEON, Preferred Practice Pattern, Under Pressure, VISION, OEC: On-Line Education Center, Professional Choices. 

Other product and company names mentioned here might be the trademarks of their respective owners. 

## Additional Information for _EyeNet Magazine_

**Copyright  
** ©2001, American Academy of Ophthalmology, Inc.? All rights reserved. No part of this publication may be reproduced without written permission from the publisher. Letters to the editor and other unsolicited material are assumed intended for publication and are subject to editorial review, acceptance and editing. 

**Disclaimer**  
The ideas and opinions expressed in EyeNet are those of the authors, and do not necessarily reflect any position of the editors, the publisher or the American Academy of Ophthalmology. Because this publication provides information on the latest developments in ophthalmology, articles may include information on drug or device applications that are not considered community standard, or that reflect indications not included in approved FDA labeling. Such ideas are provided as information and education only so that practitioners may be aware of alternative methods of the practice of medicine. Information in this publication should not be considered endorsement, promotion or in any other way encouragement for the use of any particular procedure, technique, device or product. EyeNet, its editors, the publisher or the Academy in no event will be liable for any injury and/or damages arising out of any decision made or action taken or not taken in reliance on information contained herein. 

## **Privacy Statement**   

  * We only use information collected on aao.org for Academy purposes and do not distribute this information to third parties. 
  * We deploy technology to protect the information your send us. 
  * Cookies are used to keep track of information to allow a better user experience and this information is kept confidential within the Academy. 

The American Academy of Ophthalmology has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website: **aao.org.**

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. 

Our site uses cookies to keep track of your shopping cart. We also use cookies to save and verify your password information so you don't have to register each time you visit our the Annual Meeting section. 

aao.org contains areas and forms that require user and member registration to give us contact information (like their name and email address), unique identifiers (like their social security number), financial information (like their account or credit card numbers), and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level). We use customer contact information from the registration form to send the user information about our company. 

Financial information that is collected is used to bill the user for products and services. Unique identifiers (such as social security numbers) are collected to verify the user's identity. Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. All data is only used for Academy purposes. 

This site contains links to other sites. **aao.org** is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. 

Our site incorporates forms for customers to request information, products, and services. We collect visitor's contact information (like their email address), financial information (like their account or credit card numbers), and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level). Contact information from the order form is used to send orders and information about our company to our customers. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below. Financial information that is collected is used to check the users' qualifications and bill the user for products and services. 

aao.org online surveys ask users and members for contact information (like their email address) and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level). We use contact data from our surveys to send the user information about our company. The customer's contact information is also used to contact the visitor when necessary. 

## Academy E-mail Privacy Policy

The Academy will protect your e-mail address from inappropriate use. If the Academy determines the use of your e-mail address is of benefit to its members and/or their patients, the Academy may, with the approval of its Executive Vice President, provide your e-mail address to a third party.

**_Policies Governing the Use of Academy E-mail Addresses_**

The Academy's Executive Vice President may grant permission to use Academy e-mail addresses to organizations, firms or individuals who agree to comply with the following conditions:

  1. The Academy determines if the use of e-mail addresses is of benefit to its members and/or their patients.
  2. The content of every e-mail correspondence is subject to advance approval by the Academy. A sample of each intended e-mail correspondence must be reviewed and approved by the Academy.
  3. Each set of Academy e-mail addresses will be used only once and only for the purpose approved by the Academy.
  4. An entity other than the Academy cannot use Academy e-mail addresses to create or update its own database. The e-mail address list is the property of the Academy and may not be duplicated.
  5. Use of Academy e-mail addresses does not imply Academy endorsement, and no implication of endorsement will be made in any correspondence.
  6. Academy e-mail addresses will not be made available for any communication on drugs, medical equipment or devices involving the offer of a rebate, discount, or other remuneration, which in the sole discretion of the Academy may be illegal or unethical.
  7. Academy e-mail addresses will not be made available for any communication that would tend to mislead, misinform, or deceive.

##  Security

This website has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. 

## Contacting the Website

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact: 

American Academy of Ophthalmology  

Informatics  
655 Beach Street  
San Francisco, CA 94109
